Guide to the National Book Critics Circle Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
National Book Critics Circle Records
1975-1999
YCAL MSS 878
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.42
(5 boxes)
National Book Critics Circle
Arrangement
Organized into four groupings: August 1992 Acquisition, September 1993 Acquisition, March 1994 Acquisition, and May 1994 Acquisition.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
The National Book Critics Circle (NBCC), founded 1974, is the professional association of American book review editors and critics. The NBCC presents the National Book Critics Circle Awards yearly. Individuals involved in the NBCC include Herbert Leibowitz, Nina King, and Jack Miles.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, meeting minutes, financial papers, membership records, and printed material relating to the National Book Critics Circle. The National Book Critics Circle Awards deliberations and programs are especially well documented.
Critics -- United States; Editors -- United States; Literary prizes -- United States; American literature -- 20th Century; Critics -- United States -- 20th Century; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century; King, Nina, 1941-2010; Leibowitz, Herbert A.; Miles, Jack, 1942-; National Book Critics Circle
- August 1992 Acquisition, 1975-1992; 1; 2; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 264
  Arrangement
  This portion of the collection is not arranged in any particular order.
  - National Book Critics Circle Journal volumes 1-16, 1975-1991; 6 (Box 1)
  - National Book Critics Circle Journal assorted volumes, 1990, 1992 (Box 1)
  - National Book Critics Circle Journal correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 1)
  - Awards meeting, 1987 January 12 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting, 1987 March 16 (Box 1)
  - Meetings, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting, 1989 March 10 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting, 1989 September 29 (Box 1)
  - Nominations meeting, 1990 January 8 (Box 1)
  - Awards meeting, 1990 February 12 (Box 1)
  - Annual meeting and awards ceremony, 1990 March 8 (Box 1)
  - Membership directory, 1984-1990 (Box 1)
  - Toni Morrison brouhaha, 1988-1988 (Box 1)
  - Reviewer's citation, 1984-1984 (Box 1)
  - Reviewer's citation, 1985-1985 (Box 1)
  - Citation finalists, 1986-1986 (Box 1)
  - Citation finalists, 1987-1987 (Box 1)
  - Publicity clippings, 1985-1990 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's reports and assorted, Larry Swindell and Eliot Fremont-Smith, 1984-1990 (Box 1)
  - Conarroe and Times exchange, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Stickers, 1990-1990 (Box 1)
  - Scrolls, 1985-1990 (Box 1)
  - Los Angeles Times issues, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Board correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 2)
  - Awards correspondence, 1985-1990 (Box 2)
  - Awards, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1984-1986 (Box 2)
  - Council of Writers Organizations, 1984-1986 (Box 2)
  - Invitation to join the National Book Critics Circle, undated (Box 2)
  - Journal correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 2)
  - Insurance for members, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Awards ceremonies, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - New-York Historical Society, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Presidential election, 1986-1986 (Box 2)
  - Ethics survey, 1987-1987 (Box 2)
  - Bylaws, 1984-1984 (Box 2)
  - Awards lists, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Presidential letters, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
  - Letters to the president, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence over incident involving Tom Disch, 1991-1991 (Box 2)
  - Jack Miles memos to the board, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
  - Board elections, candidates, and resignations, 1984-1989 (Box 2)
  - Nina King and presidential correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 2)
- September 1993 Acquisition, 1991-1993; 2; 0.42; (1 box)
  This portion of the collection is arranged alphabetically by file title.
  - Election ballots for the board, reviewer's citation, and best books, 1991-1991 (Box 3)
  - Organizational history, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Reviewer's citation, 1991-1991 (Box 3)
- March 1994 Acquisition, 1987-1994; 3; 1; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 387
  - Awards, 1991-1991 (Box 4)
  - Winners, 1992-1992 (Box 4)
  - Board award, 1988-1990 (Box 4)
  - Printing for the National Book Critics Circle Journal, 1991-1991 (Box 4)
  - David Lehman, 1989-1991 (Box 4)
  - Reviewer's citation, 1988-1992 (Box 4)
  - Herb Leibowitz presidential columns, 1992-1993 (Box 4)
  - Membership, 1987-1994 (Box 4)
  - Catering and venues, 1991-1994 (Box 4)
  - Awards ceremony, 1993-1993 (Box 4)
  - Memos, 1988-1993 (Box 4)
  - Dan Moldea affair, 1992-1993 (Box 4)
  - Jack Miles, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Harriet Blacker, 1993-1993 (Box 4)
  - Deborah Zaik charges against Jack Marshall (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 4)
  - Alan Ryan, 1992-1994 (Box 4)
  - Josh Rubins, 1992-1993 (Box 4)
  - Board correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous to do, undated (Box 4)
  - Meeting agenda, 1994 January 14 (Box 4)
  - Afternoon forum, 1994-1994 (Box 4)
  - Nona Balakian reviewer's citation entries not chosen for finals, 1993-1993 (Box 4)
  - Publicity, 1993-1993 (Box 4)
- May 1994 Acquisition, 1980-1999; 4; 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 392
  - Awards, 1986-1991; 5 (Box 5)
  - Awards nominees, 1992-1992 (Box 5)
  - Ethics survey, 1988-1988 (Box 5)
  - Press releases, 1980-1989 (Box 5)
  - Programs, 1992-1992 (Box 5)
  - Publicity, 1981-1990; 2 (Box 5)
  - "Writers of the Future" award panel discussion, 1987-1999 (Box 5)